https://uk.whales.org/cookie-policy/

Skip to content
As with many websites, WDC uses cookies in order to provide you with a more personalised web service. A cookie is a text-only string of information that we pass to your computer's hard disk through your web browser so that our website can remember who you are. Cookies cannot be used by themselves to identify you.
This Policy sets out what cookies are, why we use cookies on our websites and your options relating to their use.
Who are ‘we’?
We are WDC, Whale and Dolphin Conservation, a registered charity and company wholly owned and operated by WDC. A company registered in England and Wales with company number 2737421 and a charity registered in England and Wales with charity number 1014705, and Scotland with charity number SC040231. Our registered address is Brookfield House, 38 St Paul Street, Chippenham, Wiltshire SN15 1LJ.
WDC (Trading) Limited sells a range of goods through its shop and café based in Scotland, enters into corporate partnership agreements, and runs a raffle.  All of its profits are passed to WDC.  WDC (Trading) is wholly owned and controlled by WDC and all staff are employed by WDC.
When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. When services are delivered on the internet, it sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, such as your computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as ‘cookies’. They cannot be used to identify you personally.
What are ‘cookies’?
In simple terms a cookie is a small piece of information sent from our website to your computer to help us recognise it quickly. If you prefer not to accept a cookie, you can navigate the websites like a normal user. Any information gathered through the use of cookies is compiled on an aggregate, anonymous basis.
Why do we use cookies on our websites?
We use cookies so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our websites. In particular we use cookies to:
avoid lengthy registration/personalisation of the site each time you visit and personalise it to suit your requirements
recognise you when you login and make it easier for you to access your account information
estimate our audience size and patterns
ensure that you are not asked to register twice
control how often visitors see similar adverts
track preferences and to improve and update our websites
track the progress and number of entries in some of our promotions and contests
Our websites may feature embedded ‘share’ buttons to enable users to easily share articles with their friends through a number of popular social networks. These sites may set a cookie when you are also logged in to their service. We do not control the dissemination of these cookies and you should check the relevant third party website for more information about these.
Use of cookies
We use two main types of cookies on our website, session and persistent cookies. Cookies can expire at the end of a browser session (from when a user opens the browser window to when they exit the browser) or they can be stored for longer.
Session or transient cookies
These cookies allow our websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They may be used for a variety of purposes such as remembering what a user has put in their shopping basket as they browse around the site. These cookies expire after a browser session ends so are not stored longer term.
Persistent, permanent or stored cookies
These cookies are stored on a user's device in between browser sessions which allows the preferences or actions of the user across a site (or in some cases across different websites) to be remembered. Persistent cookies may be used for a variety of purposes including remembering a user's preferences and choices when using our site.
First- and third-party cookies
Whether a cookie is ‘first’ or ‘third’ party refers to the website or domain placing the cookie. First-party cookies are, simply, cookies set by a website visited by the user - the website displayed in the URL window. Third-party cookies are cookies that are set by a domain other than the one being visited by the user.  While there is no advertising on the WDC site you will find links to other sites for the purposes of processing payments, entering events or finding additional information.  Each of these sites will have its own policy and is responsible for notifying you of its cookie usage policy.
Specific cookies you may find on our website
You can find out up-to-date information which cookies are being used below.
Do I have to agree to cookies?
Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you should be able to change your browser settings to prevent that or by changing the settings in the cookie preferences on this website at anytime. You should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can set up your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. This should then give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a website if you do so. Cookies are specific to the server that created them and cannot be accessed by other servers, which means they cannot be used to track your movements around the web.
Where can I get more information about cookies and how to change my settings?
To remove Google Analytics tracking please download the plug-in for your browser.
For more information about cookies, please visit www.aboutcookies.org
For information on how to change cookies settings on your browser please visit the relevant information page:
Safari
Internet Explorer
Firefox
Chrome
Cookie Details
This cookie statement was last updated on 26th May 2020 and applies to citizens of the European Economic Area.1. IntroductionOur website, https://uk.whales.org (hereinafter: "the website") uses cookies and other related technologies (for convenience all technologies are referred to as "cookies"). Cookies are also placed by third parties we have engaged. In the document below we inform you about the use of cookies on our website.2. What are cookies?A cookie is a small simple file that is sent along with pages of this website and stored by your browser on the hard drive of your computer or another device. The information stored therein may be returned to our servers or to the servers of the relevant third parties during a subsequent visit.3. What are scripts?A script is a piece of programme code that is used to make our website function properly and interactively. This code is executed on our server or on your device.4. What is a web beacon?A web beacon (or a pixel tag) is a small, invisible piece of text or image on a website that is used to monitor traffic on a website. In order to do this, various data about you is stored using web beacons.5. Cookies5.1 Technical or functional cookiesSome cookies ensure that certain parts of the website work properly and that your user preferences remain known. By placing functional cookies, we make it easier for you to visit our website. This way, you do not need to repeatedly enter the same information when visiting our website and, for example, the items remain in your shopping cart until you have paid. We may place these cookies without your consent.5.2 Analytical cookiesBecause statistics are being tracked anonymously, no permission is asked to place analytical cookies.5.3 Marketing/Tracking cookiesMarketing/Tracking cookies are cookies or any other form of local storage, used to create user profiles to display advertising or to track the user on this website or across several websites for similar marketing purposes.5.4 Social media buttonsOn our website we have included buttons for Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Instagram to promote webpages (e.g. “like”, “pin”) or share (e.g. “tweet”) on social networks like Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Instagram. These buttons work using pieces of code coming from Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Instagram themselves. This code places cookies. These social media buttons also can store and process certain information, so a personalized advertisement can be shown to you.Please read the privacy statement of these social networks (which can change regularly) to read what they do with your (personal) data which they process using these cookies. The data that is retrieved is anonymised as much as possible. Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Instagram are located in the United States.6. Placed cookiesGoogle Analytics
Usage
We use Google Analytics for website statistics. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Google Analytics Privacy Statement.
Statistics (anonymous)
Name
_ga
Retention
2 years
Function
Store a unique user ID
Name
_gid
Usage
We use Facebook for display of recent social posts and/or social share buttons. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Facebook Privacy Statement.
Marketing/Tracking
Name
_fbp
Retention
3 months
Function
Track visits across websites
Hotjar
Usage
We use Hotjar for heat maps and screen recordings. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Hotjar Privacy Statement.
Statistics
Name
_hjid
Retention
1 year
Function
Store a unique user ID
Statistics (anonymous)
Name
_hjIncludedInSample
Retention
session
Function
Store anonymized statistics
Functional
Name
_hjSessionResumed
Retention
Function
WP Do Not Track
Usage
We use WP Do Not Track for cookie consent management. Read more
Sharing data
This data is not shared with third parties.
Functional
Name
dont_track_me
Retention
1 year
Function
Store 'do not track' signals
Stripe
Usage
We use Stripe for payment processing. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Stripe Privacy Statement.
Functional
Name
__stripe_mid
Retention
1 year
Function
Provide fraud prevention
Visual Website Optimizer
Usage
We use Visual Website Optimizer for webshop statistics and optimization. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Visual Website Optimizer Privacy Statement.
Purpose pending investigation
Name
_vwo_uuid_v2
Retention
Function
Name
_vis_opt_s
Retention
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Complianz Privacy Statement.
Functional
Name
cmplz_all
Retention
365 days
Function
Store cookie consent preferences
Name
Sharing data
This data is not shared with third parties.
Statistics
Name
prli_visitor
Retention
1 year
Function
AddThis
Usage
We use AddThis for providing social share buttons. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the AddThis Privacy Statement.
Purpose pending investigation
Name
__atuvc
Retention
13 months
Function
Store performed actions on the website
Name
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Google Tag Manager Privacy Statement.
Marketing/Tracking
Name
_gcl_au
Retention
persistent
Function
Track conversions
Optimizely
Usage
We use Optimizely for website statistics. Read more
Sharing data
This data is not shared with third parties.
Statistics
Name
optimizelyEndUserId
Retention
6 months
Function
Store a unique user ID
Buttonizer
Usage
We use Buttonizer for buttons creation. Read more
Sharing data
This data is not shared with third parties.
Purpose pending investigation
Name
buttonizer_preview_*
Retention
Function
WP Google Maps
Usage
We use WP Google Maps for maps display. Read more
Sharing data
This data is not shared with third parties.
Functional
Name
wpgmza-api-consent-given
Retention
1 year
Function
Store cookie consent preferences
WordFence
Usage
We use WordFence for website security. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the WordFence Privacy Statement.
Purpose pending investigation
Name
wfwaf-authcookie-*
Retention
Function
Wistia
Usage
We use Wistia for video display. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the Wistia Privacy Statement.
Marketing/Tracking
Name
wistia
Retention
persistent
Function
Store performed actions on the website
PayPal
Usage
We use PayPal for payment processing. Read more
Sharing data
For more information, please read the PayPal Privacy Statement.
Functional
Name
__paypal_storage__
Retention
persistent
Function
Store account details
Miscellaneous
Function
7. ConsentWhen you visit our website for the first time, we will show you a pop-up with an explanation about cookies. As soon as you click on "Save preferences", you consent to us using the categories of cookies and plug-ins you selected in the pop-up, as described in this Cookie Policy. You can disable the use of cookies via your browser, but please note that our website may no longer work properly.7.1 Manage your consent settings8. Your rights with respect to personal dataYou have the following rights with respect to your personal data:
You have the right to know why your personal data is needed, what will happen to it, and how long it will be retained for.
Right of access: You have the right to access your personal data that is known to us.
Right to rectification: you have the right to supplement, correct, have deleted or blocked your personal data whenever you wish.
If you give us your consent to process your data, you have the right to revoke that consent and to have your personal data deleted.
Right to transfer your data: you have the right to request all your personal data from the controller and transfer it in its entirety to another controller.
Right to object: you may object to the processing of your data. We comply with this, unless there are justified grounds for processing.
To exercise these rights, please contact us. Please refer to the contact details at the bottom of this Cookie Policy. If you have a complaint about how we handle your data, we would like to hear from you, but you also have the right to submit a complaint to the supervisory authority (the Data Protection Authority).9. Enabling/disabling and deleting cookiesYou can use your internet browser to automatically or manually delete cookies. You can also specify that certain cookies may not be placed. Another option is to change the settings of your internet browser so that you receive a message each time a cookie is placed. For more information about these options, please refer to the instructions in the Help section of your browser.Please note that our website may not work properly if all cookies are disabled. If you do delete the cookies in your browser, they will be placed again after your consent when you visit our websites again.10. Contact detailsFor questions and/or comments about our Cookie Policy and this statement, please contact us by using the following contact details:Whale and Dolphin Conversation
Brookfield House, 38 St Paul Street, Chippenham, Wiltshire SN15 1LJ
United Kingdom
Website: https://uk.whales.org
Email: info@whales.org
Phone number: 01249 449500This Cookie Policy was synchronised with cookiedatabase.org on 6th March 2020
